

BTech(CSE) Graduate|3+ years of experience in Software Development|Sound understanding of Python, Django, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AWS, and SQL queries|Capable of Performance Testing, Documentation, and Deployment on live site|Immediate Joiner



Current Location: Noida Total Experience: 3 Year(s) 1 Month(s)

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chandigarh, Delhi / NCR Highest Degree: B. Tech/B.E. [Computer Science and

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming / Engineering]

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Engineer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Application

Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution

Architecture, Django, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, MySQL, PyCharm, Visual Studio Code, Python, JMeter

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

Experienced Software Engineer having 3.2 years of experience with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry.

Hands-on experience of Python and Django framework.

Experience with AWS cloud service platform.

Experience in API testing using Postman.

Front end development skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery and Bootstrap responsive web design.

Familiarity with ORM (Object-Relational Mapper).

Experience in load testing using JMeter.

Basic understanding of code versioning tool, such as Git.

Work Experience

Svobodha Infinity Private Limited as Software Engineer

Sep 2020 to Dec 2020

- * Make the whole website responsive using Bootstrap and CSS3.
- * Analyzing the requirement.
- * Preparing the Use Cases document and Low-Level Design document.
- * Develop Rest APIs
- Actively involved in bug solving using defect tracking tool-JIRA.

Hexaforce Solutions as Software Engineer

Sep 2019 to Sep 2020

- * Migration of Python2 code to the latest version of Python
- * Writing test cases for the complete testing of product after migration.
- * Directly interact with the client to understand the requirement.
- * Analyzing the requirement and work on the enhancement part and develop APIs also.
- Integrated some third party API.
- * Actively involved in the deployment of code using WinMerge and WinSCP.

Subtlelabs Software Solutions as Software Engineer

Nov 2017 to Sep 2019

- * Performed all the front-end related functionality.
- * Solving existing bugs as per requirement using bug tracker Redmine.
- Writing some API and updating models.
- * Integrated third party API such as FEDEX and UPS.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computer Science and Engineering) from Uttar Pradesh Technical University (UPTU) in 2017

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
DJANGO		
HTML, CSS		
JavaScript, JQuery		
MySQL		
pycharm, visual studio code		
Python		
JMETER		
AWS Server, JIRA		
Post Man, Git, Redmine		

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time